## Amin Khodabandeh

Senior Software Architect at Capital Platforms Pte. Ltd.

amin.17@gmail.com

## Summary

I started programming with QBasic and soon found this ability on myself that I love to create something from nothing, so I started to work with other programming languages such as C and Pascal and later with Delphi and ActionScript.

I have done many projects with Delphi and SQL-Server for many organisations, thus I have earned enough experience in Database projects developing and architecture. Many of these projects still are working as well as in their region and subjects. Working on several subjects leads me to learn networks infrastructures and I get enough experience about Windows Server and Linux.

Soon I have started to develop web applications with ASP.NET with Visual Basic and C#, MVC and Web API, in the parallel side worked with PHP mostly in WordPress and Drupal. JavaScript and HTML5 open new horizons that starts my first steps going familiar with JQuery and later with AngularJS and I really enjoy during playing with them exactly the time I found Nodejs as a way to use Javascript in Back-End development.

Currently I manage a dedicated server with Microsoft Hyper-V with two guest machines on it: one CentOS and one Microsoft Windows Server. Both serves Web-Application in their fields, In CentOS I develop and maintenance more than 10 WordPress web sites.

I've been created two mobile applications by Apache Cordova in both iOS and Android finished by AngularJS that served with WordPress Restful.

My current project is a web and mobile application building up by ASP.NET, Node.js, and Ionic.

## Experience

# Senior Software Engineer at Capital Platforms Pte Ltd March 2015 - Present

- As a senior software architect my responsibilities are design, develop and implement applications with most recent technologies and make them to be stable and applicable for our customers.
- As a senior software developer, I create applications by using most recent technologies such as ASP.NET MVC and WebApi, AngularJS, RESTFUL, SQL-Server, HTML5.
- As a mentor for our teammates and colleagues to help and lead them.
- Develop and support web software and enterprise applications in the finance and online trading following range of products Stand Alone investments, Insurance Linked Platforms, QROPS, QNUPS, regular premium and general insurance products.

Senior Software Developer at Capital Platforms Pte Ltd

#### October 2014 - Present

Develop and support web software and enterprise application for customers, Technologies used ASP.NET MVC, AngularJS, JSON, SQL-Server, HTML5, CSS3

#### Founder and CTO at Omni Net of Baran

#### February 2008 - Present

Founded in 2008 in Iran, It was a startup with a mission to approach best solutions and find new ways to facilitate business accounting and IT systems problems and develop their new informatic automation structures.

Base Technologies: SQL Server, Delphi, CentOs, PHP, ASP.NET, C#

ONBCO was a member of East Azarbaijan Science and Technology Park during 3 years and had an accepted idea to create a Tabriz Rug Weaver Robot.

http://onbco.com

#### IT Trainer and Instructor

October 2000 - December 2013 (13 years 3 months)

As a trainer in this institute I teached major IT courses such as Internet Engineering, Web Developments, and Databases.

http://en.ibtc.ir/

#### CTO and Shareholder

January 2006 - September 2008 (2 years 9 months)

A Startup to bring our ideas to reality including unattended CD Multimedia Kids Trainer, Turkish to Persian Dictionary Software.

#### IT Trainer and Instructor

February 2005 - May 2008 (3 years 4 months)

As a trainer in this institute I teached graphic applications courses such as Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop.

#### Senior IT Engineer

May 2001 - September 2003 (2 years 5 months)

My responsibilities was lead my team to update and maintain our customer's pc machines always ready in both software and hardware against any unexpected problems.

### Education

Azad University (IAU)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering, 2003 - 2005

**UCNA** 

BS, Computer Software Engineering, 2000 - 2002

## Amin Khodabandeh

Senior Software Architect at Capital Platforms Pte. Ltd.

amin.17@gmail.com



Contact Amin on LinkedIn